<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[ blog | Hari Menon]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.harimenon.com/blog/categories/blog/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.harimenon.com/"/>
  <updated>2017-03-05T02:40:57+00:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.harimenon.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Hari Menon]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[me@harimenon.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A stroke of insight - a splendid talk from TED]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.harimenon.com/blog/2013/04/22/a-stroke-of-insight/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-22T19:15:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.harimenon.com/blog/2013/04/22/a-stroke-of-insight</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>You must watch <a href="http://www.ted.com/talks/jill_bolte_taylor_s_powerful_stroke_of_insight.html">this amazing TED video</a></h3>

<p>Thank you, Kiran...</p>

<iframe src="https://embed.ted.com/talks/jill_bolte_taylor_s_powerful_stroke_of_insight.html" width="640" height="360" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[An awesome write-up on Design]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.harimenon.com/blog/2013/03/27/an-awesome-writeup-on-design/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-27T11:28:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.harimenon.com/blog/2013/03/27/an-awesome-writeup-on-design</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I happened on this tweet from Sven Fuchs (<a href="https://twitter.com/svenfuchs">@svenfuchs</a>) yesterday:</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p>what a *fantastic* piece about design! <a href="http://t.co/cUObIRwK80" title="http://informationarchitects.net/blog/learning-to-see">informationarchitects.net/blog/learning-…</a> really makes me want to screw code and do more design again (thx @<a href="https://twitter.com/dotmariusz">dotmariusz</a>!)</p>&mdash; Sven Fuchs (@svenfuchs) <a href="https://twitter.com/svenfuchs/status/316692345083006977">March 26, 2013</a></blockquote>


<script async src="https://www.harimenon.com//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>


<p>And that was so delightful a read, I thought I will linklog it from here.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Twitter Cards for Octopress blogs]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.harimenon.com/blog/2013/02/23/twitter-cards-for-octopress-blogs/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-23T19:21:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.harimenon.com/blog/2013/02/23/twitter-cards-for-octopress-blogs</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The first time I heard about <a href="https://dev.twitter.com/docs/cards">Twitter Cards</a> is from <a href="https://github.com/blog/1388-github-now-supports-twitter-cards">the GitHub blog entry</a> announcing they have implemented it for all the GitHub respositories. And if you haven't heard about them, go to either of those posts and you'd get a quick overview.</p>

<p>Anyways, since the time I read that blog, I have been thinking of trying to implement it here on this blog as well as on the other website I've been actively maintaining lately - <a href="http://flickrdownloadr.com">flickrdownloadr.com</a>. Finally got around to doing it yesterday on the static pages at flickrdownloadr site (even though I am still waiting for Twitter to approve my site).</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Today, I took it one step further by implementing it here and on <a href="http://flickrdownloadr.com/blogs/">the blog there</a>, which are both built with the awesome <a href="http://octopress.org">Octopress</a> platform. Turned out to be pretty straight-forward - just add the below snippet into the <code>source/_includes/custom/head.html</code> and you should be all set.</p>

<p>``` html twitter_cards
{% if site.twitter_user %}</p>

<pre><code>&lt;meta property="twitter:card" content="summary"&gt;
&lt;meta property="twitter:site" content="{{ site.twitter_user }}"&gt;
&lt;meta property="twitter:url" content="{% if canonical %}{{ canonical }}{% else %}{{ site.url }}{% endif %}"&gt;
&lt;meta property="twitter:title" content="{% if page.title %}{{ page.title }}{% else %}{{ site.title }}{% endif %}"&gt;
&lt;meta property="twitter:description" content="{{ description | strip_html | condense_spaces | truncate:200 }}"&gt;
</code></pre>

<p>{% endif %}
```</p>

<p>P.S: Also, you would need to apply (or "opt-in") for Twitter Cards <a href="https://dev.twitter.com/form/participate-twitter-cards">here</a> <strong><em>and</em></strong> they will have to approve it for the cards to start showing up.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Auto-deploying to my Octopress blog with Travis-CI]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.harimenon.com/blog/2013/01/27/auto-deploying-to-my-octopress-blog/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.harimenon.com/blog/2013/01/27/auto-deploying-to-my-octopress-blog</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A couple weeks earlier, <a href="http://darvin.github.com/">Sergey Klimov</a> (who is <a href="https://github.com/darvin">@darvin</a> at GitHub) opened the <a href="https://github.com/imathis/octopress/issues/940">issue #940</a> at <a href="https://github.com/imathis/octopress">imathis/octopress</a>, which is more a feature suggestion than an issue.</p>

<p>Within that, he has linked to <a href="http://darvin.github.com/blog/2013/01/13/Prose_Octopress_TravisIO/" title="Prose.io + Octopress + Travis-CI + GitHub Pages = ♥">his detailed blog post</a> suggesting how the awesome <a href="https://travis-ci.org/">Travis-CI</a> could be configured to do the <code>rake generate</code> and <code>rake deploy</code> for you, when you add/update new posts to an <a href="http://octopress.org/">octopress</a> blog, even from browser-based editors like either the built-in GitHub editor, or a third-party tool like the <a href="http://prose.io">prose.io</a> editor (which is really awesome too, BTW).</p>

<p>For the uninitiated, Travis-CI is a really nice, open source, free and hosted continuous integration service that could build and run the unit tests for you, on every commit to a GitHub repository. It supports projects in a multitude of languages, as seen <a href="http://about.travis-ci.org/docs/user/getting-started/#Travis-CI-Overview">here</a>. The service allows you to configure steps that would be run <a href="http://about.travis-ci.org/docs/user/build-configuration/">before, after and during the build and test process</a>, with just one <a href="http://www.yaml.org/" title="YAML Ain't Markup Language">YAML</a> file (named <code>.travis.yml</code>) in the root of your repo. Apart from running the many unit tests in the project and letting you know how your latest check-in affected the health of the project, the Travis-CI service could also do custom build tasks like a post-build deployment. And this is what Sergey has tappped into, for use with the deployment of an Octopress blog.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>His blog post really has everything that one would need to set-up Travis-CI for automating the deployment of their blog. This post here is trying to add a couple of tweaks that were done, when I <a href="https://travis-ci.org/floydpink/harimenon.com">successfuly enabled</a> auto-deploy for <a href="/blog">this blog</a> of mine, the source of which can be seen at <a href="https://github.com/floydpink/harimenon.com">floydpink/harimenon.com</a>. (Also, this very post, is in-fact composed on a browser, thanks to <a href="http://prose.io/#floydpink">prose.io</a> service).</p>

<h4>1. Revert _config.yml</h4>

<p>As the <code>before_script</code> is using <code>rake setup_github_pages</code> task every time on Travis to setup the <em>deploy git correctly, it was overwriting the <code>_config.yml</code> <code>url</code> value to the github <code>url</code>, which would be a problem, if like me, you are deploying this to a custom domain.
``` diff </em>config.yml
 #      Main Configs       #
 # ----------------------- #</p>

<p>-url: http://www.harimenon.com
+url: http://floydpink.github.com/harimenon
 title: Hari Menon
 subtitle: Namaste. Welcome to my personal space on the world wide web!
 author: Hari Menon
<code>``
This subtle little thing was manifest only in the tweet button behavior (which fortunately, I noticed when I was trying to tweet this very post) as seen in this screenshot:
[<img src="https://i.imgur.com/jLAFiwl.png" title="Tweet button behavior" alt="Tweet button behavior">](https://i.imgur.com/jLAFiwl.png)
Instead of the correct URL -</code>http://www.harimenon.com/blog/2012/12/16/aop-for-logging-in-net/<code>, the tweet was showing -</code>http://floydpink.github.com/harimenon/blog/2012/12/16/aop-for-logging-in-net/`.</p>

<p>To fix this, we should add an additional line to revert the <code>_config.yml</code> (especially for the blogs that are hosted with cutom URLs).</p>

<p><code>diff .travis.yml
   - echo -e "Host github.com\n\tStrictHostKeyChecking no\n" &gt;&gt; ~/.ssh/config
   # Set deployment target to github pages
   - rake setup_github_pages[$REPO]
+  # To reset the 'url' to the custom domain in '_config.yml'
+  - git checkout -- _config.yml
 script:
   # Generate site
   - rake generate
</code></p>

<h4>2. Add [ci skip] to the commit message</h4>

<p>As a <em>P.S.</em> to his blog post, Sergey talks about how Travis builds the project twice once for the original commit (with the intended changes to the blog) and second because of the commit from the <code>rake deploy</code> applied by this first Travis build (all of this is because, it seems the <code>branches</code> <a href="https://gist.github.com/4522846#file-travis-yml-L1">setting</a> in the <code>.travis.yml</code> that limits it to the <code>source</code> branch only does not seem to work). And he has <a href="https://gist.github.com/4522846#file-travis-yml-L22">a clever workaround</a> in the <code>after_script</code> to stop this at the second build itself rather than going into an infinite loop - <code>'echo ''script: "ls *.html"'' &gt; public/.travis.yml'</code>. I tweaked this a little bit as below:</p>

<p>From one of the earlier encounters, I remembered that the <a href="http://about.travis-ci.org/docs/user/how-to-skip-a-build/">Travis-CI documentation</a> does detail how a specific commit could be made to skip the ci build. Just by including <code>[ci skip]</code> (including the brackets) somewhere in the commit message. So the first tweak I did is this in the <code>Rakefile</code>:</p>

<p>``` diff Rakefile</p>

<pre><code> system "git add ."
 system "git add -u"
 puts "\n## Commiting: Site updated at #{Time.now.utc}"
</code></pre>

<ul>
<li> message = "Site updated at #{Time.now.utc}"</li>
<li> message = "Site updated at #{Time.now.utc} [ci skip]"
 system "git commit -m \"#{message}\""
 puts "\n## Pushing generated #{deploy_dir} website"
 system "git push origin #{deploy_branch} --force"
```</li>
</ul>


<h4>3. Syntax changes in using the travis command line tool to encrypt deploy key</h4>

<p>Also, because I had to upgrade to the latest version of the Travis, which has slightly different command-line syntaxes now, I had to tweak <a href="https://gist.github.com/4242707">the script he has referred to</a>, to generate the <code>secure</code> argument for the deploy key. My version is as below:
<div><script src='https://gist.github.com/4631240.js'></script>
<noscript><pre><code></code></pre></noscript></div>

The difference essentially is only in the <code>ENCRYPTION_FILTER</code> environment variable, that holds the way the <code>travis</code> command line client would be used to generate the encrypted deploy key.</p>

<p>One more occasion, where I feel like I have done something <em>a la</em> a dwarf standing on the shoulders of giants.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Migrated this blog to Octopress]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.harimenon.com/blog/2013/01/18/migrated-this-blog-to-octopress/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-18T01:55:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.harimenon.com/blog/2013/01/18/migrated-this-blog-to-octopress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><blockquote><p><small><strong>Update (01/22/2013)</strong>: Perhaps I blogged too soon! I'm loving the Octopress so much, that the whole site has now been updated to be built with Octopress. So some old blogs (<a href="http://en.blog.harimenon.com">english</a> &amp; <a href="http://technology.harimenon.com">technical</a>) get redirected to the corresponding categories on the new unified blog, while some others (<a href="http://ml.blog.harimenon.com">malayalam</a> are still on blogger and are not linked from the site for the time being.</small></p></blockquote></p>

<p>This blog had been on blogger since its inception back in 2009, though it really has only a very few posts in those almost-four years. The newly found love for the <a href="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</a> blogging platform, thanks to the experience setting up the <a href="http://flickrdownloadr.com/blogs">flickrdownloadr blog</a> recently, I decided to bite the bullet and move my technical blog over.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>This <a href="http://approache.com/blog/migrating-from-blogger-to-octopress/">really nice post</a> by <a href="http://github.com/dnagir">Dmytrii Nagirniak</a> made the whole migration process really a breeze, thanks to the nifty <a href="https://gist.github.com/1765496">Blogger-Octopress migration script</a> and the simple <a href="http://www.sinatrarb.com/">Sinatra</a> <a href="https://github.com/dnagir/approache-redirects/blob/master/app.rb">redirection app</a> he has provided there. <s>Even though I ended up not using the sinatra app, because for me: a) the domain name is not changing during this migration and b) the new permalink slug in fact has additional element - which is the <code>day</code> from the published date (whereas the blogger permalink format was just <code>year</code> and <code>month</code>). So unless I hard-code all the post URLs to be redirected (which in reality I could, considering I have just 13 posts that are being moved), the redirection app I thought, is not worth it.</p>

<p>I did manualy add all the old permalinks with static meta-tag and JavaScript based redirection though. So if you watch the headers in fiddler or something while clicking this old blogger URL - <a href="http://technology.harimenon.com/2012/12/lzwCompress.js.html">http://technology.harimenon.com/2012/12/lzwCompress.js.html</a>, you would see a page come down with 200, that does either of a <code>&lt;meta http-equiv="refresh" content="0;url=..."/&gt;</code> refresh or the <code>location.replace('...')</code> from the JavaScript within, to the new URL on Octopress - <a href="http://technology.harimenon.com/blog/2012/12/06/lzwCompress.js/">http://technology.harimenon.com/blog/2012/12/06/lzwCompress.js/</a>.</p>

<p>But all the old label/category/archive links etc. (like this one - <a href="http://technology.harimenon.com/search/label/ClickOnce%20Deployment">http://technology.harimenon.com/search/label/ClickOnce Deployment</a> would  remain broken but I have decided that's how it's going to be.</s></p>

<p><blockquote><p><small><strong>Update (01/22/2013)</strong>: Both the old blogs (english and technical ones) are now being redirected with Sinatra apps made of off <a href="http://github.com/dnagir">Dmytrii</a>'s <a href="https://github.com/dnagir/approache-redirects">redirection app</a>.</small></p></blockquote></p>

<p>Hopefully, the new blogging platform would be <em>the</em> impetus that I've been waiting for to start churning up a lot of posts!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
